import { useState } from "react";
import "./App.css";
import Card from "./components/Card";
import MyBtn from "./components/Mybtn";
import Score from "./components/Score";
import Item from "./components/Item";

let num = 0;
let points = 0;
let checkedItems: string[] = [];

const cards = [
  {
    question: "Which of these movies is not based on a book?",
    answer: "Avatar",
    items: ["Little Women", "The Hunger Games", "The Godfather", "Avatar"],
  },
  {
    question:
      'Who directed the film adaptation of J.R.R. Tolkien\'s "The Lord of the Rings" trilogy?',
    answer: "Peter Jackson",
    items: [
      "Christopher Nolan",
      "Peter Jackson",
      "Steven Spielberg",
      "George Lucas",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      'In the "Harry Potter" film series, who played the character Hermione Granger?',
    answer: "Emma Watson",
    items: ["Emma Watson", "Emma Stone", "Emma Roberts", "Emma Thompson"],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of Jane Austen's novels was adapted into the movie starring Keira Knightley?",
    answer: "Pride and Prejudice",
    items: [
      "Sense and Sensibility",
      "Mansfield Park",
      "Pride and Prejudice",
      "Emma",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which 2013 film, directed by Alfonso CuarÃ³n, follows two astronauts stranded in space after their shuttle is destroyed?",
    answer: "Gravity",
    items: ["Astronomical", "Gravity", "Black Hole", "Orbit"],
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the title of the 1979 Ridley Scott film that introduced the iconic extraterrestrial creature known as the Xenomorph?",
    answer: "Alien",
    items: ["E.T. - The Extra-Terrestrial", "The Thing", "Prometheus", "Alien"],
  },
  {
    question: 'Who directed the 2014 science fiction film "Interstellar"?',
    answer: "Christopher Nolan",
    items: [
      "Christopher Nolan",
      "Steven Spielberg",
      "Quentin Tarantino",
      "Alfred Hitchcock",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      'Who narrates the animated classic "How the Grinch Stole Christmas!"?',
    answer: "Boris Karloff",
    items: ["Jim Carrey", "Will Ferrell", "Boris Karloff", "Tom Hanks"],
  },
  {
    question:
      'In "A Charlie Brown Christmas," what kind of tree does Charlie choose?',
    answer: "A real tree",
    items: ["A fake tree", "A real tree", "A giant tree", "A Christmas bush"],
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which 1989 film features a dysfunctional family trying to have a "good old-fashioned family Christmas"?',
    answer: "National Lampoon's Christmas Vacation",
    items: [
      "National Lampoon's Christmas Vacation",
      "A Christmas Story",
      "Scrooged",
      "Home Alone 2: Lost in New York",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which 1999 sci-fi film directed by the Wachowskis explores the concept of simulated reality?",
    answer: "The Matrix",
    items: ["Star Trek Two", "The Matrix", "Resident Evil", "Vanilla Sky"],
  },
  {
    question:
      'In the movie "Home Alone," what is the name of the young boy who is accidentally left behind when his family goes on vacation for Christmas?',
    answer: "Kevin",
    items: ["Buzz", "Marvin", "Charlie", "Kevin"],
  },
  {
    question:
      'In the movie "Blade Runner," what is the term used for bioengineered beings that are virtually identical to humans?',
    answer: "Replicants",
    items: ["Robots", "Terminators", "Replicants", "A.I."],
  },
  {
    question:
      'In "The Fifth Element," who plays the character Korben Dallas, a former special forces major?',
    answer: "Bruce Willis",
    items: [
      "Jason Statham",
      "Bruce Willis",
      "Vin Diesel",
      "Sylvester Stallone",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      'In the "Star Wars" saga, what is the name of the desert planet where Anakin Skywalker and Luke Skywalker were raised?',
    answer: "Tatooine",
    items: ["Dimidium", "Halla", "Bambaruush", "Tatooine"],
  },
  {
    question: 'Who was known as the "King of Hollywood" during the Golden Age?',
    answer: "Clark Gable",
    items: ["Clark Gable", "Cary Grant", "Humphrey Bogart", "Henry Fonda"],
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which legendary actress starred in "Gone with the Wind" and won an Oscar for her role?',
    answer: "Vivien Leigh",
    items: [
      "Olivia de Havilland",
      "Hattie McDaniel",
      "Alicia Rhett",
      "Vivien Leigh",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which iconic film director was responsible for classics like "Citizen Kane" and "The Third Man"?',
    answer: "Orson Welles",
    items: ["Orson Welles", "Alfred Hitchcock", "John Ford", "John Huston"],
  },
  {
    question:
      'Who played the role of Rick Blaine in "Casablanca," one of the most celebrated films of the era?',
    answer: "Humphrey Bogart",
    items: ["Paul Henreid", "Humphrey Bogart", "Peter Lorre", "Claude Rains"],
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which film won the first Academy Award for Best Picture in 1929?",
    answer: "Wings",
    items: ["7th Heaven", "The Parade", "The Racket", "Wings"],
  },
];

function App() {
  const [score, setScore] = useState(0);

  const [card, setCard] = useState(cards[num].question);

  const goBack = () => {
    if (num > 0) {
      num--;
      setCard(cards[num].question);
    }
  };

  const nextCard = () => {
    if (num < cards.length - 1) {
      num++;
      setCard(cards[num].question);
    }
  };

  function checkGuess(guess: string) {
    if (guess === cards[num].answer && !checkedItems.includes(guess)) {
      setScore(++points);
      checkedItems.push(guess);
      if (points == 20) {
        alert("You Won!!!");
      } else alert("Correct!");
    } else {
      if (checkedItems.includes(guess)) {
        alert("You've already guessed the answer.");
      } else {
        alert("Wrong!");
      }
    }
  }

  return (
    <>
      <div className="App">
        <div className="row">
          <div className="col">
            <MyBtn onClick={goBack}>Back</MyBtn>
          </div>
          <div className="col">
            <Card>{card}</Card>
            {cards[num].items.map((element, index) => {
              return (
                <Item key={index} onClick={() => checkGuess(element)}>
                  {element}
                </Item>
              );
            })}
          </div>
          <div className="col">
            <MyBtn onClick={nextCard}>Next</MyBtn>
          </div>
        </div>
      </div>

      <Score>{score}</Score>
    </>
  );
}

export default App;
